Your Highness,
太子殿下
Lady Yunxi is here to visit you.
路大小姐前来探望
Your Highness.
殿下
Yunxi.
云溪
I heard that there was an assassin in the hunting ground yesterday,
我听闻昨日在猎场出现刺客
so I came to visit you.
前来探望你
Are you all right?
你可安好
I'm fine.
我倒是没什么事
But my brother almost got hurt.
但王兄差点受伤
Have you found any clue, Your Highness?
那殿下可有查到什么线索
There is no substantial progress yet.
还没有什么实质性的进展
But now that people have heard about this.
不过现在百姓听说了此事
They are under the misconception that I am at odds with my brother,
都在误会我与王兄不和
and that's why I've done this.
才下此毒手
You and Lord Jin are so close,
你与晋王兄弟情深
you would never do such a thing.
绝不会做出这种事情
You don't need to think about it much.
你也无须多虑
I'm sure the truth
我相信这件事
will come out one day.
一定会有真相大白的一天
This is
这个
what I found on the site.
便是在现场找到的
It should be left behind by the assassin during the fight.
应当是刺客在拼杀时所留之物
These tassels
看这剑穗
do not likely come from an ordinary family.
不像是普通人家所佩戴
This should belong to some important minister's house in court.
应当是朝中重臣府上所有
Whose is it?
究竟会是谁呢
My Lady.
大小姐
I heard that an assassin assaulted Lord Jin
听说昨日在太子猎场
at the Crown Prince's hunting ground yesterday.
有刺客刺杀晋王
You have been my father's subordinate for so many years,
你长随父亲左右
please take care of him.
千万要护他周全
Please don't worry, My Lady.
大小姐放心
It is my job
保护大人
to protect His Grace.
是齐翼的分内之事
I will do my best.
齐翼定当尽力
If there's nothing else, I'll leave now.
若没什么事齐翼先告退了
Is that him?
难道是他
Yunxi?
云溪
Your Highness,
殿下
this thing does look familiar to me,
此物我确实眼熟
but I can't remember who owns it for now.
但一时想不起来是谁所有
Your Highness,
殿下
we found out that
属下查到
there were indeed some guards wearing tassels
当日确实有侍卫佩戴流苏穗子
around the hunting ground that day.
出现在猎场周围
However, there was no way to check this person,
不过此人无从查起
I wonder if Your Highness wants to check all the ministers' guards.
不知殿下是否查抄众臣侍卫
No.
不可
Such a large-scale operation
如此兴师动众
would only make the assassins realize something,
只会打草惊蛇
and would also make the people panic,
还会令百姓恐慌
so that the assassins could not be caught.
更抓不到刺客
Now there are a lot of discussions in Qiyuan continent.
那现在启元大陆议论纷纷
If we do not find out the truth as soon as possible,
如不尽快查到真相的话
I am worried that the people
属下担心这百姓们
will lose their minds.
人云亦云啊
Your Highness,
殿下
I may know who it is.
云溪或许知道是谁
Who is it?
是谁
My Lady,
小姐
there is some good news.
有好消息
The assassin was found?
猎场刺客找到了
No, not really.
那倒没有
But today the Master is not in the Mansion,
不过今日老爷不在府上
Lady Yunxi is also not here.
大小姐也不在
Is that so?
是吗
Great!
太好了
I'll go find Nangong.
那我要去看看南宫
I don't know how he is recovering now.
也不知道他恢复得怎么样了
Then you need to dress up. My Lady.
那小姐您可要好好打扮一番
Dress up beautifully to meet His Highness.
美美地去见晋王殿下
You have sealed your magic power for Qingqing.
为了卿卿封了灵力
Do you regret it?
后悔吗
No at all.
完全不后悔
But Lu Hongzhu is focusing on you now.
但是路鸿竹现在盯上你
And it will become more and more difficult in the future.
以后只会越来越难
How can you protect yourself
你没了灵力
and Qingqing,
怎么保护你自己
without your magic power?
怎么保护卿卿啊
Qingqing once said,
卿卿曾经说过
not everything has to be solved
不是所有的事情
by magic power.
都要用灵力来解决
Although without magic power, I still have a smart brain.
没有灵力我还有脑子
Qingqing's magic power is getting stronger and stronger now.
卿卿现在灵力是越来越强了
I am very pleased.
我很欣慰啊
So this is how it looks,
潇洒的南宫一昕痴情起来
when an unrestrained person like you has such an infatuation.
是这样啊
How dare you say that about me?
你好意思说我吗
Your love for Wanqing
你对菀青的深情
is no less than my love for Qingqing.
不比我对卿卿少
I... I won't talk to you anymore.
我 我不跟你说了
I'm going to arrange flowers now.
我插花去
Where did
这个南宫一昕
this Nangong Yi Xin go?
到底去哪儿了
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了
Going outdoors in such terrible physical condition,
身体还没恢复好就出门
you might get a cold.
着凉了怎么办
Look at you, just like an angry woman.
瞧你像个受气小媳妇似的
Don't worry, I've recovered.
放心吧 我好了
Don't be angry.
你别生气了嘛
Smile. Smile.
笑一个 笑一个
But I'm really worried about you.
可是我真的很担心你
I'm glad that you're worried about me.
你担心我 我很欣慰
But don't keep frowning.
但别老皱眉啊
Alright, no more jokes.
行了 不跟你开玩笑了
Follow me.
带你去个地方
Qingqing,
卿卿
you remember this place, right?
你还记得这儿吧
Of course.
当然记得了
That day you left with anger,
那日你憋着气就走了
I did not know what you were angry about.
我都不知道你在气什么
Qingqing,
卿卿
do you know why
你知不知道
I kept my anger that day?
那天我为什么憋气啊
I don't know.
不知道
Qingqing,
卿卿
That day
那一天
I've been waiting for you to say that,
我一直在等你说出那句话
but you never did.
却一直没等到
Today in the same place,
今天还是在这儿
I want to tell you,
我想先告诉你
Qingqing,
卿卿
♫A single kiss from you makes my heart feel like it's in turmoil♫
我喜欢你
I want to be with you forever and ever.
我想永远永远和你在一起
Me too.
我也是
It's really beautiful here.
这儿真的好美啊
So comfortable.
好舒服呢
It depends on who you stay with.
那还不是得看跟谁待在一起
Stay with me longer if you feel comfortable.
舒服就多陪我待会儿
What a great day.
今天天气多好啊
The quiet atmosphere
四周这么安静
is perfect for wind blowing and boating.
就适合划划船 吹吹风
Yes, it is.
是啊
But why is this boat not moving?
可是这船怎么都不动啊
This is my first time in a row.
我第一次划船
Slow down.
慢点
It turns out
原来还有你南宫一昕
there are things you can't do.
做不好的事情
I've found it.
这回可算是被我逮到了
You'll see.
你等着啊
Once I get the hang of it, I'll be fast.
等我熟悉熟悉给你来个快的
Qingqing,
卿卿
what are you thinking about?
想什么呢
I was thinking that
我在想
it would be nice if time stopped at this moment.
要是时间停止在这一刻就好了
What a peaceful time.
岁月静好
Qingqing,
卿卿
I promise you that
我答应你
I will settle everything as soon as possible,
我一定尽快解决完所有事端
and then I will never leave you again.
然后便再也不离开
We will go to live a quiet and peaceful life.
我们去过平淡安宁的生活
I believe you.
我相信你
But now the Qiyuan continent is very dangerous.
可是现在启元大陆很危险
I can't take everything into account.
我不能所有的事情都顾及上
So promise me
所以答应我
you'll hurry back to your training in Youhuang, okay?
赶紧回幽簧里训练好不好
Now my magic power has increased quite a lot,
我现在灵力提升了不少
so I can protect myself,
我可以保护好我自己
and even you.
甚至是南宫你
I will never separate from you again.
卿卿和南宫再也不要分开了
But I'm worried about you.
可是我很担心你
I know that you and my father have some conflicts.
我知道你和我爹有一些分歧
Although I don't know what your conflicts are.
虽然我不知道分歧是什么
I don't want you
但是我不希望
to keep going on like this.
你们一直这么下去
You are the closest people to me,
你们都是我最亲的人
so I don't want you
我不希望你们对对方
to harbor hatred for each other.
怀有恨意
It's just that not everything
只是不是所有的事情
is as simple as you think.
都像你想得那么简单
It's raining.
下雨了
It's raining heavily.
下好大
Your Highness.
太子殿下
Qi Yi,
齐翼
do you still recognize this?
可还认得这个
Why did you assassinate Lord Jin?
为何行刺晋王
You don't want to talk?
不说
Lingyu,
凌宇
prepare the magic whip.
上灵鞭
You're not going to say anything?
还不说
Whip him!
给我打
How dare you assassinate Lord Jin
皇家重地
in the royal place!
竟敢公然行刺晋王
Who did you work for?
你受了谁的指使
What was your intention?
你是何居心
Your Highness,
殿下
after all, Qi Yi is a member of Lu's Mansion,
齐翼毕竟是路府的人
so I am also responsible.
云溪也难逃其责
Can I talk to him for a second?
让我和他说几句可好
Qi Yi,
齐翼
if you don't explain clearly,
你若再不解释清楚
the Empress
王后知道了
will definitely involve all of us in the Lu's Mansion
势必将我们路府上上下下
if she finds out.
全部牵连其中
Have you forgotten about the fusang fruit?
你难道忘了扶桑果的事吗
Who asked you to do this?
到底是谁指使你的
Why did you plan the assassination?
你们为何要谋划刺杀之事
I don't believe this was your intention.
我不相信这是你本意所为
It was motivated by love.
因情而起
Who are you in love with?
对谁的情
I love Lady Qingqing.
我中意二小姐
I don't want Lady Qingqing
不想让二小姐
to be with Lord Jin.
与晋王殿下在一起
So I wanted to kill him.
所以想要杀了他
No one instructed me to.
没有任何人指使
Qi Yi,
齐翼
what are you talking about?
你在胡说什么
Do you really think I'm stupid?
真当本太子蠢笨不成
You don't want to say the truth, do you?
不说实话是吧
Lingyu,
凌宇
whip him!
给我打
Qi Yi clearly told a lie.
齐翼分明在说谎
What truth is he hiding?
他到底在隐藏什么
Did this have something
难道这事
to do with my father?
与父亲有关
Have a seat.
坐
How did you get hurt?
怎么会受伤
What happened?
发生了何事
I was ordered to send General Han's army
小的奉王爷之命
to the No Magic Valley.
将韩将军手下送往废灵谷
When I was passing by a thin strip of sky,
在经过一线天的时候
Lu Hongzhu's subordinates suddenly appeared
路鸿竹的人突然出现
and robbed General Han's subordinate.
把人给劫走了
I had something to go out for today,
本王今日有事外出
so I ordered Xiao Wu and a servant
命小武和一名家丁
to go to the No Magic Valley to purchase.
去废灵谷采购
After they returned to the Mansion I heard that
回府后听说
Xiao Wu was injured,
小武受了伤
and that servant was captured by Lord Lu back to the Lu's Mansion.
家丁还被路大人压回了路府
That was strange.
此事有些古怪
Your Grace,
路大人
are you dissatisfied with me?
你是不是对本王不满
I came here to ask for an explanation.
本王特地来讨个说法
Your Highness, please don't be angry.
晋王息怒
It is true that
您府上家丁的事
I do not know about it.
老臣确实不知
But I did catch a rebel today,
不过今天的确是抓了一个逆党
and that's the murderer of General Han.
是杀害韩将军的凶手
I would like to ask,
老臣倒想问问
how did Xiaowu get together with him?
小武怎么会跟他在一起呢
The murderer?
凶手
What evidence do you have?
有什么证据啊
I do have evidence,
证据自然是有
but
只不过呢
it's not convenient to disclose to Your Highness now.
现在不方便透露给王爷
Because the relationship between Xiaowu and this person is too close.
因为小武与此人的确私交过密
Then I would like to meet this murderer.
那本王倒想见识见识这个凶手啊
I don't think that's necessary.
我劝晋王还是不必了
Don't draw fire to yourself.
不要引火烧身
Your Grace,
路大人
His Highness has arrived.
太子殿下有请
Got it.
知道了
Go tell His Highness,
去跟殿下说
I'll be right there.
我收拾一下就过去
Yes, Your Grace.
是
I urge you to think carefully about
我劝晋王还是考虑清楚
whether you are related to this murderer.
跟这个凶手是不是有关系才好
Fu,
阿福
send Lord Jin off.
送送晋王
Yes, Your Grace.
是
Your Highness, please.
殿下 请
Your Grace.
大人
Take the body out and throw it away.
你们去把尸体抬出来扔了
Yes, Your Grace.
是
Go!
快去
Father.
父王
The emperor is dead.
王上驾崩了
Let me go!
放开我
The emperor is dead! Father!
王上驾崩了 父王
Wake up!
你醒醒
Father!
父王
It was you
杀我父王的人
who killed my father, Lu Hongzhu.
果然是你 路鸿竹
Your Highness,
殿下
Lord Lu has arrived.
路大人到了
Greetings to Your Highness.
太子金安
Father.
爹
I want to know what mistake Qi Yi has made,
不知齐翼做错了什么
let me know
告知老臣
and I will punish him severely.
老臣定当严惩不贷
Explain to me,
你跟本王解释一下
why Qi Yi would
为何齐翼
assassinate my brother in my hunting ground?
会在本王的猎场刺杀王兄
Why did Your Highness say that?
殿下何出此言哪
This thing belongs to Qi Yi.
此物便是齐翼的
Even Yunxi can be righteous
连云溪都能够大义凛然
and expose the sinners regardless of personal feelings,
不顾私情地揭露罪人
what else do you want to say?
路大人还有什么好说的
Are you going to
难不成
cover up Qi Yi?
你要包庇齐翼不成
Report to Your Highness that
禀殿下
I did this alone.
此事是齐翼一人所为
It has nothing to do with His Grace.
和大人无关
Qi Yi,
齐翼
you just tell the truth.
你就如实说了吧
Why would you assassinate Lord Jin?
为何要刺杀晋王
Your Grace,
大人
I have been in love with Lady Qingqing for a long time
齐翼爱慕二小姐已久
and recently found out that Lord Jin and Lady Qingqing are very close.
近日发现晋王与二小姐交往密切
I was jealous,
齐翼心生妒忌
so I did this.
所以出此下策
How can you deny it?
事到如今你还在狡辩
Do you think that you can take all the blame
你以为你这么说
on yourself
便能够把所有罪责
by saying this?
都揽到自己一个人身上吗
Alright,
好
if that's the case,
既然如此
then I'll make it happen for you.
那本王便成全你
Qi Yi murdered the royal family
齐翼谋害王室
and deserved to be executed.
理应处斩
Your Highness!
殿下
Please be merciful.
请殿下手下留情
Murdering the royal family is a capital crime,
谋害王室是死罪
and Qi Yi deserves it.
齐翼死不足惜
Your Highness!
殿下
Qi Yi just didn't figure out the stakes of the matter.
齐翼或许只是一时糊涂
Although I was the one who turned Qi Yi in,
虽然是云溪告发齐翼
he grew up with us
但他与我们
after all.
毕竟从小一起长大
I hope Your Highness
还请殿下看在路府上下
will spare Qi Yi's life
都对您忠心的份上
for the sake of our family's loyalty to you.
饶齐翼一命
Father,
爹
Qi Yi has been your subordinate for so many years,
齐翼他跟了您多年
you know him best.
他的为人您最清楚
He has always listened to you
一直以来他对您说一不二
and has been loyal to our family.
对我们路府忠心耿耿
How could he do the thing that would degrade us?
他怎么会做出有辱路府的事情
After hearing what Yunxi said,
听云溪的意思
could it be that Lord Lu instructed Qi Yi to do this?
莫非是路大人指使齐翼干的
Well,
罢了
things have come to this point,
事已至此
I'll tell you the truth.
老臣就实说了
That's right,
不错
it was me who instructed Qi Yi to set up an ambush at the hunting ground
正是老臣指使齐翼去猎场设伏
to wait for an opportunity to assassinate Lord Jin.
伺机刺杀晋王
Why did you use such a cruel method
路大人为何要用如此邪恶的手段
to target my brother?
去针对王兄
My brother is my closest brother,
王兄是本王至亲的兄弟
and what you did is so cruel to him.
你这是在残害本王的手足
Besides,
况且
my brother suffered the accident in my hunting ground.
王兄是在本王的猎场上出的事
How do people think of me
你这样
after you do that?
让百姓如何看待本王
What do you
路大人这是要将本王
want me to do?
置身于何地啊
I did this
老臣这么做
for Your Highness.
都是为了殿下您呢
Your Highness,
殿下
You are pure in nature
您性情纯良
and treat Lord Jin as your elder brother.
把晋王当兄长看
But Lord Jin does not see you as a brother.
但晋王可没把您当兄弟看
He has evil intentions.
他居心叵测 心怀不轨
My brother and I have always been honest with each other.
我和王兄一向坦诚相待
Honest?
坦诚相待
Does Your Highness know that
那殿下可知
Lord Jin has been harboring
晋王一直在窝藏
the assassin of General Han?
刺杀韩将军的凶手
We have been unable to find this murderer
这个凶手我们一直找不到
because he was hiding in Lord Jin's Mansion.
因为他就藏在晋王府内
That's impossible!
不可能
He's not that kind of person.
王兄他不是那样的人
He is not interested in dynastic affairs,
他无心朝事
and will not harbor any fugitives.
更不会私藏什么逃犯
Your Highness,
殿下
the face is known and the heart is not known.
知人知面不知心呢
Do you
路大人这么说
have any evidence?
可有证据
Unfortunately,
可惜
the murderer tried to escape to the No Magic Valley today,
今日那凶手本想逃往废灵谷
and killed himself
被我手下发现以后
after my subordinates found him.
自杀了
Your Highness,
殿下
do you know why Lord Jin
可知晋王为何一直与小女
has been entangled with my daughter?
纠缠不清
My brother also adores Qingqing.
王兄也喜欢卿卿
I know it.
这本王知道
That's not true.
此言差矣
Lord Jin has always been a loose cannon,
晋王一向放荡不羁
how could he make so many sacrifices for my daughter?
怎会为小女做到如此地步
He can do this for only one thing,
他能做到如此只为一件
the magic power stone.
那就是灵力石
It is still too early
仅凭一己猜测
to conclude that my brother has evil intentions
便断定王兄居心叵测
based on your speculation alone.
未免为时尚早
I will find out
这件事
the truth.
本王自会查清楚
But until then,
但是在此之前
I hope you will not
本王希望路大人
act rashly again.
不要再轻举妄动
Yes, Your Highness.
是
It's true
这件事
that I have been too hasty in this matter.
的确是老臣操之过急了
But my loyalty to Your Highness...
不过老臣对殿下的忠心
Stop it!
好了
That's it,
今日之事
for now.
暂且如此
You all leave now.
都先下去吧
But it is urgent to get rid of Lord Jin.
但除掉晋王刻不容缓啊
No need to say more.
不必再说
I'll make my own decision.
我自有决断
Qi Yi.
齐翼
Your Grace,
大人
I have not done my job well,
属下办事不力
so Your Grace was humiliated in front of the Crown Prince today.
让您今日在太子面前受了折辱
Please punish me, Your Grace.
还请大人责罚
Stand up.
起来吧
Be more careful in the future.
以后做事小心些
Go take a rest.
你先下去休息吧
Thanks Your Grace.
多谢大人
Yunxi,
云溪
come with me to the study.
你随我到书房来
Father, I admit that
爹 我承认
I was the one who told the Crown Prince
是我告诉太子
that the evidence he found on the hunting grounds
他在猎场上找到的证物
was Qi Yi's.
是齐翼的
Alright,
好了
this matter ends here.
这件事呢到此为止
I will not pursue your fault,
爹不会追究你的过错
on the contrary,
相反
your righteousness and straightforwardness
你的仗义直言
is what I appreciate.
正是爹所欣赏的
Thank you, Father.
谢谢爹
I will definitely be careful with my words in the future.
我以后一定会谨言慎行
I know your affection
你对太子那点心思
for the Crown Prince.
爹还不知道吗
The purpose of everything we do
我跟你所做的一切
is actually the same.
其实目的是一样的
It's all for the Crown Prince.
都是为了太子
All this is to ensure the Crown Prince
能够顺利登上王位
can ascend the throne smoothly.
你能明白爹的苦心吗
I just don't understand one thing.
只是云溪有一事不明
You said that
您方才在大殿上说
Lord Jin
晋王殿下
was related to the murderer of General Han.
与杀害韩将军的凶手有关
But why did Lord Jin want to kill General Han?
可晋王殿下为何要杀韩将军
This thing was obscure,
此事隐秘
and the Crown Prince regarded Lord Jin as a good brother,
太子又拿晋王当好兄长看待
so just now in the hall,
所以方才在大殿之上
I didn't say that much.
我就没有多说
Before the Emperor died,
先王在仙去之前
he left a secret imperial edict.
曾留下过一道密诏
A secret imperial edict?
先王密诏
Yep.
对
But no one knows the contents of the secret imperial edict.
但是密诏的内容无人知晓
What I have found out is that
我现在查到的是
General Han had access to the secret imperial edict during his lifetime.
韩将军在生前曾接触过密诏
And now the secret imperial edict belongs to Lord Jin.
而现在密诏落在晋王手里
No wonder you are so suspicious of Lord Jin.
难怪爹对晋王如此忌惮
Although we don't know
虽然我们都不知道
what the imperial edict says,
密诏里说的是什么
Lord Jin's possession
但是密诏在晋王手里
of the imperial edict is still a major problem.
始终是个大患
If you let him get the magic power stone,
若再让他得到灵力石
then I'm afraid this throne
那这王位
will no longer belong to the Crown Prince.
恐怕就真的不是太子的了
Father, don't worry.
爹 您放心
I will do my best to assist you
我一定会尽全力帮您
in helping the Crown Prince keep his throne.
帮太子保住王位
You can leave now.
去吧
The hunting ground assassination case has been identified,
猎场一事已经查明
and Lord Lu's subordinate, Qi Yi is the murderer.
是路大人的手下齐翼所为
Qi Yi has no vendetta against me.
这齐翼跟我无冤无仇
Have you found out why?
有没有查出什么原因
After being punished with a magic whip,
齐翼在受到一场灵鞭刑罚之后
Qi Yi confessed the truth.
如实招出原委
According to him, he had fallen in love with Qingqing,
他对卿儿产生爱慕之情
and when he saw that you were close to her,
见王兄与卿儿亲近
so he hated you.
于是暗自生恨
This is what led to the hunting ground assassination.
才产生了猎场刺杀一事
I see.
原来是这样啊
Mingyang,
铭炀
do you believe his words?
你相信他的说辞吗
I have my doubts about it,
我也对此有所犹疑
but the evidence is solid.
但是证据确凿
I don't think
我看他所说
what he said was a pretext.
也不像是托辞
Qingqing is so lovely
卿儿灵动可爱
and Qi Yi has grown up in the Lu's Mansion since he was a child.
齐翼自小在路府长大
So it's understandable that
他对卿儿产生爱慕之意
he has feelings for her.
也可以理解
Yep.
是啊
Mingyang,
铭炀
you've worked hard.
辛苦你了 调查这事
Your magic power is strong.
王兄灵力高强
You have the seventh level of magic power.
七级灵力傍身
No one in the Qiyuan continent can be more powerful than you.
启元大陆无人出其右
Moreover, you are very good at writing,
况且王兄的文采也不输任何人
but why do you not want to get involved in politics?
为何一直不愿过问政事
If you are interested in the throne,
王兄若对王位有意
I am willing to give it up.
我也愿意让出
I have never been
我对王位呢
interested in the throne.
从来就没什么兴趣
Did you really spend all these years in the No Magic Valley
王兄这些年在废灵谷
just for fun?
当真只是游山玩水
Have you found out where the magic power stone is?
可有查到灵力石的下落
In the past few years, the Empress and Lu Hongzhu
这几年王后和路鸿竹
have been prejudiced against me.
对我一直都有偏见
If I look for magic stones in the No Magic Valley,
如果我在废灵谷查灵力石
it is a trouble for me.
那不是自找麻烦吗
Mingyang,
铭炀
Lord Lu has assisted you for so long.
路大人在你身边辅佐了那么久
Have you picked up his suspicious habits?
你莫非沾染了他多疑的习性
I always act directly,
铭炀行事一向坦荡
don't compare me with Lord Lu.
不要拿我和路大人相比
In addition, Lord Lu is my teacher,
况且路大人是我师父
We should speak and act
说话做事
with respect to him.
总还是要留几分情面
Right or wrong, good or bad, you have to feel with your heart,
这个是非善恶得用心去感受
do not be deceived by others.
莫要被蒙蔽了双眼
Are you saying that I can't tell right from wrong?
王兄这是在说我不辨是非吗
You're too over.
此言未免太过
Looks like it's not a good day for chatting.
看来今日不适合聊天
Get some rest.
王兄好好休息
I'm going to leave now.
铭炀告辞
Such a big deal,
齐翼行刺王爷这么大的事
I can't believe
竟然就这样轻飘飘
it ended so easily.
用几记灵鞭揭过了
Lu Hongzhu is now simply in control of everything.
路鸿竹现在简直是一手遮天
Listen to what he said just now,
你听听他刚才的说辞
is it not directed by Lu Hongzhu?
不就是受路鸿竹指使嘛
How could the Crown Prince think so?
太子怎会这么想
He was fooled by Lu Hongzhu.
被路鸿竹蒙蔽了呗
My Lady,
小姐
you are so worried today.
您今日忧心忡忡的
Is it because you are worried about the Crown Prince?
是在担心太子殿下吗
I was worried
我是在担心
if Lord Jin was really going to compete with the Prince for the throne.
晋王是否真的要和太子抢夺王位
[Youhuang]
师父您知不知道
what magic power will leave a black lotus mark on your palm
什么功法施用之后
after you cast it?
会在掌心留下一个黑色的莲印
Are you talking about the black lotus mark?
你说的莫非是黑莲印
As far as I know,
据为师所知
this magic power
此术法
is one of the magic power that
乃是启元大陆
banned by the Qiyuan continent.
禁用的灵力术法之一
With this kind of magic power,
用此术可以将灵力
the magic power can be forcibly instilled into the opponent's brain.
强行灌输至对方大脑中
In the end, that person will die due to a severe headache.
对方会因为头痛剧烈而亡
The most damaging aspect of this magic power is that
而此术最为阴损之处在于
he can search for memories of those
他可以搜查
who have a lower level of magic power than him.
低于自己灵力等级之人的记忆
Make people's memory confused.
使人记忆一片混乱
Yixin,
一昕
why are you suddenly interested in this?
你为何突然对此术有兴趣
Master,
师父
do you remember
您还记不记得
the secret imperial edict I received from General Han's subordinate?
我从韩将军手下得到密诏一事
Of course.
当然
That day, Lu Hongzhu assassinated General Han.
当日路鸿竹暗杀韩将军
When General Han's subordinate came out,
他的那个手下跑出来之后
he handed over the secret imperial edict and then fainted.
将密诏交给我便晕倒
I brought him back to my Mansion for secret treatment,
我将其带回府中秘密治疗
but just a few days ago
可就在前几日
Lu Hongzhu learned of his whereabouts.
路鸿竹知道了他的行踪
So I wanted to send him to the No Magic Valley,
所以我想将其送至废灵谷
but I didn't expect he would be killed on the way.
可没想到半路遭到了劫杀
I saw his corpse,
我看过他的尸体
and he had this mark on his hand.
他的手中就有此印记
Why did Lu Hongzhu
路鸿竹如此赶尽杀绝
want to kill all of them?
意欲何为呢
Father!
父王
Wake up!
你醒醒
I saw my father die
当年我亲眼所见
that year,
父王薨逝
and he had this mark on his hand.
他的手中就有此印记
Was the death of Emperor Nangong caused by Lu Hongzhu?
南宫王之死是因为路鸿竹
In fact, I have suspicions about
其实对于路鸿竹的所作所为
what Lu Hongzhu did.
我早有怀疑
But I don't have any evidence to confirm it.
但我没有证据无法确认
If Lu Hongzhu has searched for the memory
如果路鸿竹已经搜查了
of General Han's subordinate,
韩将军手下的记忆
then he must have known about the secret imperial edict.
那他肯定已经知道密诏一事
If he had known about this,
如若路鸿竹知晓此事
he would not have gone easy on you.
他势必不会对你手下留情
Yixin,
一昕
now danger is coming,
如今风雨欲来
you have to be careful.
万事小心为上啊
Qingqing.
卿儿
Are you going to meet Lord Jin with the cake?
你拿着糕点是要去见晋王
Do you know that Lord Jin is now an enemy
你可知道晋王他现在与爹爹
of our Father and our entire family?
与我们整个路府为敌
He covets the throne
他觊觎王位
and is too ambitious.
狼子野心
You so close contact with him
你这样与他密切接触
will harm yourself.
把自己折进去不说
And if it involves our whole family,
若是牵连整个路府
you have no way to make up for it.
你没有办法弥补的
It's okay for you to like the Crown Prince,
你喜欢太子
but don't think of all those
但是不要把所有
who are related to his interests
与他利益相关的人
as imaginary enemies.
都想成假想敌
Nangong is not that kind of person.
南宫他不是那样的人
He intends to plot a rebellion,
晋王他意欲谋反
can't you see that?
难道你看不出来吗
Or you has already known it,
还是你看出来了
but just want to pamper him?
却要故意纵容他
In the future, it will be convenient for you to become the Empress.
日后好坐上你的王后宝座
Don't think of everyone
不要把所有人
as so cunning.
都想的城府那么深
I just
对于南宫
simply like him,
我只是单纯的喜欢他
that's all.
仅此而已
Well then,
那好
since you have no other ideas,
既然没有别的想法
you should not contact him any more.
那你以后就不要与他接触
That's what father thought.
这也是爹爹的意思
Does everything father says have to be right?
爹说的话就一定都对吗
I only believe in what I see,
我只相信我自己眼睛看到的
what I hear,
耳朵听到的
and what I feel.
和我的心感受到的
Nangong is not the kind of person you are talking about.
南宫他不是你口中所说的那种人
You!
你
Qingqing.
卿儿
My Lady,
小姐
don't be angry
您不要因为二小姐
with her.
气坏了自己的身子啊
She has absolutely no regard for your feelings
她完全不顾及您的感受
and no regard for the safety of the family.
又不顾及路府的安危
She's just selfish
她就是自私自利
and thinks she's great.
不知天高地厚
My Lady!
小姐
You sealed your magic power for Qingqing?
你竟为了卿儿封了灵力
Now Lu Hongzhu has tried to harm you.
如今路鸿竹已经盯上你了
How can you deal with him
你没有灵力
if you don't have any magic power?
如何对付得了他
During this period of time,
这段时间
you might as well stay here to recuperate.
你不如留在幽簧里休养
I will ask someone to find the antidote to the poison.
为师托人去找解毒之法
Master,
师父
you don't usually deal with these things.
您一向是不问世事的
I can't involve you in this issue.
我不可能因为一己之私连累您
Don't worry,
您放心
I already have a solution for Lu Hongzhu's matter.
路鸿竹的事情我已经有办法
There is just one thing that
只是有件事情
I really need your help.
确实要麻烦师父
Is that about Qingqing?
卿儿
That's right.
没错
Now that Lu Hongzhu has known that
如今路鸿竹已经知道
the magic power stone is inside Qingqing,
卿卿体内有灵力石
and he tries to get it by all means.
想方设法地想要得到它
He has already used some bad tactics,
已经用了一些下贱的手段
so I am worried that he will do whatever he can to get the stone.
所以我担心他会不择手段
Even
甚至于
sacrificing Qingqing's life.
牺牲卿卿的性命
Now the best way is to
现在最好的办法
bring her back to this place
就是让她回到您这儿
and continue to cultivate the magic power.
继续修炼灵力
There have been many infatuated people since ancient times.
人生自古有情痴
It is rare that
难为你到这个时候
you are still thinking about the safety of Qingqing at this time.
还先考虑卿儿的安危
Your Highness,
王爷
you are back.
您回来了
Lord Sikong has been waiting for you for a while.
司空大人等了您好一会儿了
Okay.
好
Nangong, you're back!
南宫 你回来了
Any news from No Magic Valley?
废灵谷有没有消息啊
Yes.
有
In order to kill the Li An Guild Leader,
这路鸿竹为了追杀利安门主
Lu Hongzhu has already started to kill  people in No Magic Valley.
已经在废灵谷大开杀戒
He also said that
他还放话
he would do whatever it takes
不惜一切代价
to find Li An Guild Leader.
一定要找到利安门主
It's Lu Hongzhu again.
又是这个路鸿竹
What's going on?
发生什么事了
In fact, Lu Hongzhu is the murderer
其实路鸿竹
who killed my father.
就是杀我父王的凶手
What?
什么
Didn't Emperor Nangong die of illness?
南宫王不是病逝的吗
My father died
父王死的时候
with a special mark on the wound.
身上伤口处有特殊的印记
I remember that very well.
我记得很清楚
And the special power used by Lu Hongzhu
而路鸿竹用的特殊功法
is able to create the mark.
就能留下来此印记
Lu Hongzhu is so ambitious
路鸿竹狼子野心
and so inhuman.
其心当诛
Lu Hongzhu has always been cautious,
路鸿竹他一向行事谨慎
but now he has destroyed the relationship between the Qiyuan continent
如今他破坏了启元大陆
and the No Magic Valley,
和废灵谷的关系
and is determined to find Li An Guild Leader.
一心想要找到利安门主
Although obsession can drive people forward,
执念虽然可以催人奋进
it can also cause them to lose their minds.
但是也可以使人迷失心智
So I want to use this incident to
所以我想利用这件事情
reveal the true face of Lu Hongzhu.
彻底地揭开路鸿竹的面目
But,
可是南宫
have you ever thought about Qingqing?
你有想过卿卿那边吗
After all, Lu Hongzhu is her father.
路鸿竹毕竟是她父亲
Nangong,
南宫
you're here.
你来了
Didn't we agree to
不是说好了
meet here at noon?
午时在这里见面的吗
The sun is almost down,
太阳都快落山了
why are you so late?
你怎么才来啊
Did something happen to you?
你是不是发生了什么事
Nothing happened.
没有
By the way,
对了
Xiaowu said that you like hazelnut cakes.
小武说你喜欢吃榛子酥
I made these myself,
这是我亲手做的
have a try.
你尝尝
I don't like sweet things.
我不喜欢吃甜食
What's wrong with you today?
你今天到底怎么了
You're like a different person.
就像变了一个人一样
Let's not see each other for a while,
最近我们先别见面了
I have to go to the No Magic Valley to take care of some things.
我要去废灵谷处理一些事情
I'll go with you.
那我跟你一起去
I miss
正好
the kids there too.
我也很想废灵谷的孩子们
And Wanqing, Xiaoyi.
还有菀青 小乙
Don't go to No Magic Valley for a while.
你暂时就不要再去废灵谷了
Although your magic power has improved,
虽然你灵力有提升
but you still have a lot of aspects that need to be refined.
但还有很多东西需要精进
The most important thing for you now
眼下你最重要的是
is to follow the master in Youhuang to continue to cultivate.
去幽簧里跟师父继续修炼
Then I will go with you to the No Magic Valley first,
那我先跟你去废灵谷
and then go find the master.
再去找师父也不迟啊
Why do you have to follow me?
你为何一定要跟着我
If I take you with me,
我如果带上你
I can't do anything at all.
我根本没办法做事
What's wrong with you?
你今天到底怎么了
Everything I said and did was wrong.
我说什么做什么都是错
You just don't want to see me, do you?
你就是不想见到我是不是
That's right.
是啊
That's good that you understand.
你明白就好
You're too hurtful.
你过分了
If you don't like these hazelnut cakes,
这榛子酥你不喜欢吃
just think of me as a waste of time.
就当我是白白浪费时间
Lady Qingqing is back.
二小姐回来了
What happened to Lady Qingqing?
二小姐这是怎么了
My Lady,
小姐
didn't you go to meet Lord Jin?
您不是去见晋王殿下了吗
Stop it.
别说了
What happened?
怎么了
Why are you so upset?
您怎么这么不高兴
Nangong Yixin
南宫一昕
is really inexplicable today.
他今天莫名其妙
Not only was he two hours late,
不仅迟到了两个时辰
but he was also unusually indifferent to me.
还对我冷言冷语
My Lady,
小姐
don't think too much.
您别多想
Maybe Lord Jin
兴许是晋王殿下
was in some kind of trouble?
遇到了什么烦心事呢
He was so gentle to me two days ago,
明明前两天还对我那么温柔
but today he is so indifferent  to me.
今天就对我冷言冷语
Do you think he doesn't like me anymore?
你觉得他是不是变心了
After all, he is so popular,
毕竟他这么受欢迎
he may be attracted to others.
也可能被别人吸引了
Is it really like the storybook?
是不是真像话本里说的那样
It is useless to pay sincerely,
痴心总错付
once someone's got your heart, it will not be cherished.
一旦得到了就不会珍惜了
My Lady,
小姐
Lord Jin is not the kind of man
晋王殿下可不是那种
who is amorous.
朝三暮四的男人
He must have his reasons for doing so.
他这么做肯定是有他的原因的
Think carefully,
您再仔细想想
what did Lord Jin say to you?
晋王殿下都对您说了什么
Is he suddenly indifferent to me
突然对我冷淡
because he doesn't want me
难道是因为
to go to the No Magic Valley with him?
不想让我跟他去废灵谷
Last time I went to the No Magic Valley,
毕竟上次去完废灵谷
my father caught me back
被我爹抓回来
and sent me to the Manghuang forest.
之后还被罚去了莽荒森林
I also dragged him to be punished by the Empress.
还害得他被王后责罚
Maybe it's because of these.
兴许是这样吧
Lord Jin
晋王殿下
probably doesn't want you to get into trouble.
可能是不想让您惹上麻烦
But what is he going to do in the No Magic Valley?
可是他去废灵谷干什么呀
And he didn't even let me follow him,
而且还一定不让我跟着
which is very strange.
奇怪得很
Your Highness,
王爷
Lady Qingqing is here.
卿卿小姐来了
I brought you your favorite red bean cakes.
我给你带了你最爱吃的红豆酥
Qingqing knows that
卿卿明明知道
I like hazelnut cakes.
我喜欢的是榛子酥
Why did she bring in the red bean cakes?
这会儿怎么又拿来了红豆酥
Qingqing,
卿卿
you're not angry anymore?
这么快就消气了
I am generous.
我这不是大人有大量嘛
When did you learn how to make red bean cakes?
你什么时候学会做红豆酥的
I learned from my elder sister.
我这是跟大姐学的
Didn't you not want to see me
你不是在沐心园的时候
and ignore me
不想见我
when you were in the Muxin Garden?
不想理我吗
Isn't that just a pissed off remark?
那不是气话嘛
Do you really don't want to see me anymore?
难道你还真的不想见我了
She is not Lu Qingqing,
她并不是路卿卿
but Lu Yunxi.
而是路云溪
What is the purpose
扮作卿卿来这里
of her coming here dressed as Qingqing?
到底有何目的啊
I heard from my father that
我听爹说
today General Murong
今日慕容将军
talked something about General Han and his subordinates.
说了韩将军和他手下的事
You have such a good relationship with General Murong,
你跟慕容将军关系这么好
did he tell you anything?
他可有告诉你些什么
General Murong?
慕容将军
That's right!
对了
General Murong told me
慕容将军说
not to eat anything I was given,
千万不要轻易吃别人给的东西
and not to answer
更不要回答
these hostile questions.
别人不怀好意的问题
Is that true?
是吗
By the way,
对了
Sikong Ying brought a lot of fun things
司空影从废灵谷
from No Magic Valley.
带了很多好玩的东西来
Just in the side room,
就放在偏房
I'll go get you some.
我给你拿一些
Okay.
好 那你去吧
Unfortunately,
特别不巧
I just arrived at the side room
我刚到偏房的时候
and found that Xiaowu had locked the door.
就发现小武把门给锁了
I guess he thought there would be burglars.
估计他觉得会有贼进来吧
I'm going to go back home.
我先回去了
If father knows I'm out,
爹如果知道
he'll reprimand me again.
又要训斥我了
You're leaving so soon?
这么快就要走了
Just stay a little longer.
再多待会儿
I really have to go.
我真的得走了
Qingqing,
卿卿
do you know that why your father
你知不知道你爹
tried to prevent us from seeing each other?
为何千方百计阻止我们见面
Why?
为何
Because he knows very well that
因为他清楚地知道
you and I can't be together.
你我根本不可能在一起
He's the man who killed my father.
他是我的杀父仇人
What are you talking about?
你在胡说些什么
How is that possible?
爹怎么可能呢
My father has a good heart
爹心地善良
and he is loyal to the Emperor Nangong.
对南宫王族忠心耿耿
How could he do such a thing?
怎么可能做出这种事情
Your Highness must have made a mistake.
晋王殿下你一定是弄错了
I wish I was wrong.
我也希望我弄错了
But General Han's letter
但是韩将军的信里
clearly states that it is your father,
清清楚楚地写着你爹
Lu Hongzhu.
路鸿竹
He had committed a terrible crime.
罪行滔天
Your Highness seems to drink a lot
晋王殿下刚刚似乎喝了很多酒
and say a lot of nonsense.
说了很多醉话
You should get some rest.
你快休息吧
I'm going to go back.
我先回去了
Fortunately, I was prepared.
幸亏我早做了准备
At this point,
事到如今
the plan to get rid of Lu Hongzhu can not be delayed.
除掉路鸿竹的计划不能再拖了
I need to make sure that Qingqing will get back to Youhuang as soon as possible.
要让卿卿尽快回到幽簧里
It's the safest place for her.
那里对她来说最安全
You did a great job.
此事做得甚好
My dear Xi,
溪儿
did Lord Jin notice anything
你去拿密诏之时
when you went to get the secret imperial edict?
晋王可曾察觉
No.
没有
Did you find anything else?
有没有其他发现
Do you know why your father
你知不知道你爹
tried to prevent us from seeing each other?
为何千方百计阻止我们见面
Why?
为何
Because he knows very well that
因为他清楚地知道
you and I can't be together.
你我根本不可能在一起
He's the man who killed my father.
他是我的杀父仇人
My dear Xi.
溪儿
Father.
爹
All you have to do now
你现在要做的事情
is keep an eye on your sister.
就是盯紧你妹妹
Until the magic power stone appears,
在灵力石现世之前
she must not be allowed to be with Lord Jin.
绝对不能让她和晋王在一起
Yes, father.
是 爹